<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Large Government of Canada IT projects</title>
    <link>https://large-government-of-canada-it-projects.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Large Government of Canada IT projects</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 20:27:23 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://large-government-of-canada-it-projects.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2022 Data</title>
      <link>https://large-government-of-canada-it-projects.github.io/2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 20:27:23 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://large-government-of-canada-it-projects.github.io/2022/</guid>
      <description>Jump to the data
This data was collected in response to a written question in the House of Commons from April 25, 2022. The question read:
 Q-505² — April 25, 2022 — Mr. Lake (Edmonton—Wetaskiwin)
With regard to ongoing or planned government IT projects with a budget over $1 million: what are the details of each project, including the (i) project description and summary, (ii) total budget, (iii) estimated completion date?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About pt. 2</title>
      <link>https://large-government-of-canada-it-projects.github.io/post/index-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 12:55:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://large-government-of-canada-it-projects.github.io/post/index-2/</guid>
      <description>Are large IT projects likely to be successful? Of the 192 projects that appear in multiple datasets, 86% are behind schedule, 9% are on schedule, and 5% are ahead of schedule based on the estimated completion dates provided.
Among projects from 2016 and 2019, the following proportion were either completed, on schedule, or ahead of schedule:
 73% of projects smaller than $10M 59% of projects between $10M and $100M 39% of projects over $100M  Of the 2016 and 2019 projects that were over $100M, 61% were either behind schedule or not listed in the 2022 data despite an estimated completion date later in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019 Data</title>
      <link>https://large-government-of-canada-it-projects.github.io/2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 12:49:13 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://large-government-of-canada-it-projects.github.io/2019/</guid>
      <description>Jump to the data
This data was collected in response to a written question in the House of Commons from May 1, 2019. The question read:
 Q-2460 – May 1, 2019 – Mr. Lauzon (Stormont-Dundas-South Glengarry)
With regard to ongoing or planned government IT projects over $1 million: (a) what is the list of each project, including a brief description; and (b) for each project listed in (a), what is the (i) total budget, (ii) estimated completion date?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2016 Data</title>
      <link>https://large-government-of-canada-it-projects.github.io/2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 11:58:26 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://large-government-of-canada-it-projects.github.io/2016/</guid>
      <description>Jump to the data
This data was collected in response to a written question in the House of Commons from June 16, 2016. The question read:
 Q-266 – June 9, 2016 – Mr. MacKenzie (Oxford)
With regard to existing or planned government IT projects over $1 million: (a) what is the list of each project including a brief description; and (b) for each project listed in (a), what is the (i) total budget, (ii) estimated completion date?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About pt. 1</title>
      <link>https://large-government-of-canada-it-projects.github.io/post/index-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 20:49:35 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://large-government-of-canada-it-projects.github.io/post/index-1/</guid>
      <description>Combined Data Jump to the data
This data was collected in response to three written questions in the House of Commons, from June 2016, May 2019, and April 2022. Each question asked federal government departments to report ongoing or planned IT projects over $1M.
These responses were collected in three sessional papers: 8555-421-266, 8555-421-2460, and 8530-441-13-505-b. Sessional papers are public information; they can be requested by emailing the Library of Parliament.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Table data</title>
      <link>https://large-government-of-canada-it-projects.github.io/post/table/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 20:49:35 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://large-government-of-canada-it-projects.github.io/post/table/</guid>
      <description>List of Government of Canada IT projects over $1 million Self-reported by departments. Download this data in CSV format.
  Department Project Name Original Budget Latest Budget Change in Budget % Change Original Estimated completion date Latest Estimated completion date Change in completion date (years) Estimated status    Agriculture and Agri-Food Canada Departmental Client Relationship Management (CRM) Software (a.k.a. AgriClient) $2,812,101 (2022) $2,812,101 (2022)   July&amp;nbsp;31,&amp;nbsp;2022 July&amp;nbsp;31,&amp;nbsp;2022  new  Agriculture and Agri-Food Canada BioMOB (Biological Collections and Data Mobilization) – Work Package 3 Data Integration and Information Sharing $4,571,000 (2022) $4,571,000 (2022)   March&amp;nbsp;31,&amp;nbsp;2023 March&amp;nbsp;31,&amp;nbsp;2023  new  Agriculture and Agri-Food Canada Boardroom Modernization $2,408,600 (2022) $2,408,600 (2022)   March&amp;nbsp;31,&amp;nbsp;2024 March&amp;nbsp;31,&amp;nbsp;2024  new  Agriculture and Agri-Food Canada SAP Cluster Solution $6,441,134 (2019) $6,441,134 (2019)   June&amp;nbsp;25,&amp;nbsp;2019 June&amp;nbsp;25,&amp;nbsp;2019  completed  Agriculture and Agri-Food Canada Canadian Agricultural Library Corporate and Rare Book Collection Digitization $1,830,000 (2016) $1,830,000 (2016)   March&amp;nbsp;31,&amp;nbsp;2019 March&amp;nbsp;31,&amp;nbsp;2019  completed  Agriculture and Agri-Food Canada Data Integration and Information Sharing $1,175,000 (2019) $1,175,000 (2019)   April&amp;nbsp;28,&amp;nbsp;2020 April&amp;nbsp;28,&amp;nbsp;2020  completed  Agriculture and Agri-Food Canada e-Discovery Solution $1,235,000 (2019) $1,235,000 (2019)      unknown (no dates specified)  Agriculture and Agri-Food Canada Email Transformation Initiative $1,369,000 (2016) $1,369,000 (2016)   December&amp;nbsp;31,&amp;nbsp;2016 December&amp;nbsp;31,&amp;nbsp;2016  completed  Agriculture and Agri-Food Canada Streamline Grants and Contributions Program Administration $2,601,765 (2019) $2,601,765 (2019)   March&amp;nbsp;29,&amp;nbsp;2022 March&amp;nbsp;29,&amp;nbsp;2022  completed  Agriculture and Agri-Food Canada Grants and Contributions Digital Platform (GCDP) – Release 1 $11,195,560 (2019) $21,289,200 (2022) $10,093,640 90.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
